

User Experience Designer www.graceux.com graceuxd@gmail.com 585-729-0290 New York, NY

Good design is about creating pathways to resolve conflicts— it's bridging the gap between what people want to do, what they actually do, and what works for society at scale.

## **EDUCATION**

## Rochester Institute of Technology

September 2011-December 2014

Master of Fine Arts - Computer Graphics Design Thesis: Real-Time Feng Shui (interactive 3D web application)

# Beijing Information & Technology Science University

September 2007-July 2011

Bachelor of Engineering - Industrial Design

## **SKILLSET**

Interview, Research

Wireframe - Sketch, Photoshop

Prototype - Invision, Axure, HTML, CSS, JavaScript

Design - Photoshop, Sketch, Indesign, Blender

Interactive Demo - HTML, CSS, JavaScript

Animation - Muse, PricipalMac, After Effects

Testing, Documentation

## PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

## Originate | Senior UX Designer

January 2016-Present | New York, NY

- Responsible for the BlackRock web redesign; user research; creating personas, wireframes interactive designs and concept testing; providing visual design directions blackrock.com | blackrock internal brand guide
- Lead UX design for 6fusion computing platform 6fusion.com
- Develop UX guidelines for Originate through concept testing and creating interactive designs and prototypes with documentation catering to client requirements

## Liveperson | Senior UX Designer

October 2014–January 2016 | New York, NY

- Redesigned and aligned company website, campaign
  websites information architecture with business strategy
  (i.e. annotations for responsive wireframes, interactive
  prototypes and demo)

  accpi.org | holdnomore.org | livepers on.com
- Responsible for LP mobile app UX, includes personas, user scenarios, UX specs, task flows, wireframes, mockups, prototypes, localization, accessibility, visual design and
- Increased website conversion rates on pricing page, SEM landing page with in-depth user research and UX solutions

## Ideation LLC | UX Designer

design patterns

October 2013-August 2014 | New York, NY

- Created low and high-fidelity mockups on paper, with Photoshop and Axure, and implemented UX/ Visual design documentation
- Developed and designed brand and usage guidelines (i.e. optimized images, formatted text, and created interactive prototype with Invision)

#### StartFast Venture Accelerator | Multimedia Designer

May 2013-August 2013 | Syracuse, NY

- Led branding design for StartFast, Falcon, Calester and Glyphr companies
- Redesigned mobile UI/UX and promotional website for Falcon applications

#### **PUBLICATIONS**

## Explore Fengshui

- A Real-Time Learning Experience

December 2014 | Lap Lambert Academic Publishing ISBN: 978-3-659-79954-9

Exploring feng shui: The 3D Real-time Experience is an interactive 3D design project that introduces daily feng shui tips to college students, office workers, and anyone who wants to learn how feng shui can enhance their lives. This project uses Web GL technology that runs on any computer with an up-to-date, modern browser.

## Concept Testing: What You're Doing Wrong & 5 Ways to Do It Better

December 2015 | Medium.com

## 3 Problems with Apple's Weather App — and How to Fix Them

February 2016 | Medium.com

#### **HONORS**

- 2015 Adobe Design Achievement Awards:
   Web and Application Categorie
- · RIT Graduate Merits Scholarship
- · Beijing Excellent Thesis Project (High Honor)
- · China National Scholarship (Highest Honor)
- · 2008 Beijing Olympics Excellent Leadership

## PRIMARY FIELDS OF INTEREST

## Platform

Web application design, responsive website design, mobile application design

## Industry

Marketing, digital production, education, e-Commerce

#### PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

## RIT Academic Support Center | Graduate Web Designer

November 2012-May 2014 | Rochester, NY

- Led UX design for Academic Support Center
- Completed user research on international students for the Academic Support Center through the creation of personas, user scenarios and storyboards rit.edu/studentaffairs/asc/

## Lenovo Design Center | Associate Interactive Designer

June 2011-September 2011 | Beijing, China

 Assisted the UX design team; created low-fi wireframes; conducted usability testing; refined web interface for Lenovo smartphones by introducing touch and voice interaction systems

## Oak Pacific Interactive Company | Design Intern

June 2010–September 2011 | Beijing, China

 Worked on Yu Jian, an online dating platform owned by the company; assisted the design directors with mockup designs and IA testing

### **VOLUNTEERING**

#### Dress for Success New York

October 2015-Present | New York, NY

- Help female workers in the information technology industry improve their portfolios and interview skills
- Work on UX and visual design for the organization's official website

#### FeedingNYC

October 2014-October 2015 | New York, NY

 Helped organize FeedingNYC events; delivered meals to local households and homeless shelters on Thanksgiving

#### 2008 Olympics

June 2008–September 2008 | Beijing, China

 Worked as a customer service manager's assistant; led a team of 12 students serving visitors in the Beijing National Stadium square, which was known as the Bird's Nest